lexisnexis.com 2017-11-07

# Privacy Policy | LexisNexis

**1\. About This Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy explains how the personal information collected when you use the websites, mobile applications and other services that link to this privacy policy (each, a “Service”) will be used by the LexisNexis company that owns or administers the Service. This privacy policy may be supplemented by additional privacy statements, terms or notices set forth on certain areas of the Service.

**2\. Collection of Information**

The Service collects information from you in two ways: directly from your input and automatically from your use.

The types of personal information that the Service collects directly from you depends on how you interact with the Service and may include:

  * Contact details, such as your name, email address, postal address and phone number;
  * Account login credentials, such as usernames and passwords;
  * Payment information, such as a credit or debit card number;
  * Educational and professional background;
  * Comments, feedback and other information you submit to the Service; and
  * Interests and communication preferences.

The Service also automatically collects information about how you use the Service and may include:

  * Computer, device and connection information, such as IP address, browser type and version, operating system, mobile platform and unique device identifier and other technical identifiers;
  * Usage data, such as click stream data, including date and time stamp, and referring and exit pages, search terms you used and pages you visited or searched for on the Service; and
  * For location-aware Services, the region, city or town where your device is located in order to provide you with more relevant content for where you are in the world.

We may use and disclose information that does not reveal your identity or permit direct association with any specific individual, such as browser and device information, anonymous usage data and aggregated information, for any purpose, except where we are restricted by law. If we combine non-personal information with personal information, the combined information will be treated as personal information for as long as it remains combined.

We collect this data through our servers and the use of cookies and other technologies. You can control cookies through your browser’s settings and other tools. However, if you block certain cookies, you may not be able to register, login, or access certain parts or make full use of the Service.

**3\. Use of Your Information**

We may use your personal information to:

  * Process and fulfill a transaction or order;
  * Provide technical, product and other support and to help keep the Service working, safe and secure;
  * Respond to your requests, inquiries, comments and concerns;
  * Provide, evaluate and improve the Service, its advertisements and promotional campaigns and our other products and services and to develop new products, services and benefits;
  * Offer you customized content and individualized personalization of the Service to make it more relevant to your interests and needs;
  * Notify you about changes or updates to the Service and our other products and services;
  * Provide you with special offers and other information about the Service as well as other products, events and services of ours, our affiliates, and non-affiliated third parties;
  * Invite you to participate in surveys, sweepstakes, competitions and similar promotions;
  * Identify usage trends and for data analysis, including for purposes of research, audit, reporting and paying royalties and license fees to third-party providers, such as authors and other copyright holders and content distributors, and determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns, or in other ways to which you have expressly agreed in a customer agreement; and
  * Comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

We may also match or combine the personal information that you provide with information that we obtain from other sources or that is already in our records, whether collected online or offline or by predecessor or affiliated group companies, for the purposes described above.

**4.  Sharing **of Your Information****

We may share your personal information with:

  * Our affiliates, trading names and divisions within the LexisNexis group of companies worldwide (for a list, visit [//www.lexisnexis.com/offices](https://www.lexisnexis.com/offices)) and certain RELX Group companies that provide technology, customer service and other shared services functions; and
  * Our service providers, suppliers, agents and representatives, including but not limited to, editors, payment processors, customer support, email service providers, IT service providers, mailing houses and shipping agents;

to process the information for us based on our instructions and in compliance with this privacy policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

We also may share your personal information with our affiliates and with sponsors, joint venture partners and other non-affiliated third parties, including entities for which we are acting as an agent, licensee, application host or publisher, that wish to send you information about their products and services that may be of interest to you, as determined by your choices and communications preferences.

If you access the Service through an institution-sponsored subscription, your personal information and certain usage data gathered through the Service may be shared with your institution for the purposes of usage analysis, subscription management and compliance, cost attribution and departmental budgeting.

If you access an application on the Service through a license agreement with the application’s service provider, certain of your personal information will be shared with the service provider so that it can provide you the application, subject to the terms of the service provider’s license agreement and privacy policy

We also may disclose your personal information:

  * To (i) meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or other legal obligation; (ii) detect, investigate and help prevent security, fraud or technical issues; (iii) enforce and protect our rights and properties; or (iv) protect the rights, property or safety of our users, employees and others; and
  * If LexisNexis, the Service or a related asset or line of business is acquired by, transferred to or merged with another company.

The Service may let you post and share personal information, comments, materials and other content. Any information you post or disclose publicly may be collected and used by others, may be indexable by search engines, and might not be able to be removed. Please be careful when disclosing personal information in these public areas.

**5\. Your Choices and Communications Preferences**

You can manage your communications preferences when you register with the Service, by updating your account preferences, by using the “opt-out” or unsubscribe mechanism or other means provided within the communications that you receive, or by contacting us. We reserve the right to notify you of changes or updates to the Service whenever necessary.

**6.  Accessing **and Updating Your Information****

The Service may allow registered users to directly access the account information they provided and make corrections or updates to that information upon login at any time. The accuracy of such information is solely the responsibility of the user.

You may also request access to and correction of other personal information about you that you have directly provided to us through the Service. To protect your privacy and security, we may require you to verify your identity.

If you request to deactivate your account or delete your personal information, we will endeavor to fulfill your request in accordance with our policies but some personal information may persist in backup copies for a certain period of time and may be retained as necessary for legitimate business purposes or to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

Access to personal information that LexisNexis may gather from public records and other sources is subject to applicable laws and our [consumer and data access policies](http://www.lexisnexis.com/privacy/for-consumers).

**7\. Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 or target the Service to children under 13.

**8\. Data Security**

We use a variety of administrative, physical and technical security measures intended to safeguard your personal information.

**9\. Cross-Border Transfer**

Your personal information may be transferred to, accessed from and stored in servers and facilities located in your region or another country. We take steps intended to ensure that the information continues to be protected wherever it is located.

Certain U.S. entities within the LexisNexis group of companies have certified certain of their services to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. Please view these entities’ Privacy Shield Notice [here](http://www.relx.com/documents/policies/privacy-shield.pdf). To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view these entities’ certification, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/).

**10\. Changes**

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted on this page with an updated revision date.

**11\. Contact**

If you have any questions, comments or requests regarding this privacy policy or our processing of your information, please contact:

Last updated:  August 1, 2017

[Copyright](https://www.lexisnexis.com/terms/copyright.aspx) © 2017 LexisNexis
